# Rabindra Nath Sahoo

Software Engineer of 13 years' experience with strong track record in delivery. Performed to a high level in both leadership and technical capacities. Extensive experience in all phases of software development lifecycle using both Waterfall and Agile methodologies. Proven track record of working within aggressive deadlines and challenging conditions to achieve success on small and large-scale projects. Indian, living in the UK.

# **Education**

1999-2003

**Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Communication Engineering**; BPUT(ODISHA, INDIA)

# **Certification & Training**

20052007

Earned Java Certified Programmer 1.4 conducted by Sun Microsystems; Earned Business Component Developer Certification (EJB 2.0) conducted by Sun Microsystems;

# **Key Technical Skills**

Tools / Technologies	Commercial Experience	Last Used
Java 6	10 Years	2018
Java 8	2 Years	2018
Junit/Mackito/dbUnit	10 Years	2018
ESB (Jboss FUSE)	5 Years	2018
OSGI/Karaf	5 Years	2018
JAX-RS - (Apache CXF / Jersy)	3 Years	2017
JAX-WS - (Axis2 / Apache CXF)	7 Years	2018
EIPs - (Apache Camel)	4 Years	2017
Messaging – (JMS / MDBs / Active-MQ)	5 Years	2018
C.I - (Jenkins / Sonar / Maven)	5 Years	2018
Version Control (Subvsersion/GIT)	10 Years	2018
Framework – (Spring-MVC, Spring-Batch, JSF)	5 Years	2017
ORM - (JPA / Hibernate)	6 Years	2018
JBPM (JBoss Business Process Management)	4 Years	2018
Spring-Boot	2 Years	2018

Microservices	2 Years	2018
DBMS (Oracle / MySQL / PostgreSQL)	10 Years	2018
App Servers - (Weblogic/Websphere/JBOSS EAP/PORTAL)	12 Years	2018
XML - (XSD / XSLT / JAXB)	7 Years	2018
OAD / UML / Design Patterns	10 Years	2018

# Corporate Experience

Since October 2013

Lead Java Developer for Rural Payment and Services ARE. (Scotland, UK)

- Roles
  - Oct 2013 Jan 2015 Programmer
  - Feb 2015 July 2016 Team Lead, Senior Programmer
  - Aug 2016 Present Onsite Lead, Technical Specialist
- Experience
  - Production of design documentation which adequately describes use case implementation, engineering patterns, services.
  - Application of Object Orientated Analysis and design principles, SOLID design principles and SOA principles.
  - Working with the RedHat technology stack (Portal, Fuse ESB, BRMS).
  - Working closely with the solution architects and contributing to the domain model and object relational mapping integration.
  - Ensuring the code produced adheres to an acceptable design standards by working with the development build teams, regular code reviews and mentoring when required.
  - Identifying any potential issues and providing feedback to the business analysts and product owners.
  - Regularly reviewing the as-is architecture against industry best practices and drive change using POCs
  - Involved in Performance improvement, Memory Leak analysis and resolution with thread/heap dump analysing and fixing memory leak issues.
  - Working with an Agile, Scrum methodology to ensure delivery of high quality work with three weeks iteration
  - Involved in Low level design, unit test and functional enhancements to the product.
  - o Peer code reviewing. Code maintenance and refactoring. Defect resolution.
- Technologies
  - JBOSS Fuse, JPA / Hibernate, Apache CXF(SOAP), Apache Camel, Spring, Spring-Batch, Active-MQ, Oracle 11g, Jenkins, Sonar, Maven, XML, JSON, Junit, dbUnit, Mockito, Jira.

January 2013 to July 2013

## Senior Java Developer for Bell\_TV

This project is a team of 2 developers working on a Change Request of a live project to optimise the billing system for on-demand movies.

Experience

- Worked with a team of two to design and implement the new functionality to a complex distributed messaging platform, and to deliver the next major release of the product, using web service/EJB 2 applications
- Participated in code review, deployment and testing as per the requirement.
- Technologies
  - Web-service (IBM Websphere), MQ and Oracle DB, JPA / EJB 3.0, SVN, Junit, Oracle.

January 2012 to January 2013

#### Senior Java Developer for British\_Telecom

Java Developer for a team of 10 developers working on an infrastructure project to develop a Knowledge based diagnostics(KBD) and Deployment solution for an ESB.

#### • Experience

- Worked with a team of eight to ten on significant refactors enhancing scalability, functionality, robustness and testability of core T2R (Trouble to Resolve) features.
- Involved in development of multiple CR (Change Request) and core features of the project.
- Involved with team mentoring including peer reviewing of code and design.
- Participated in deployment of project in NBT, Pre-SIT, SIT and UAT environment.

#### Technologies

Mule ESB, Active-MQ, Apache Web Server, Maven, Jenkins

June 2008 to Dec 2011

## Senior Java Developer for Logica\_All\_Payment\_Solution

This is a product for Standard Bank of South Africa(SBSA) and USSA\_Bank to create a high value payment solution and enabling gateway for SWIFT/ ISO 20022

#### Experience

- Implemented a database domain migration to allow for efficient transfer of existing customer data to our new domain.
- Participated in code review, project management and testing as per the requirement.
- Involved in gateway development of ISO 20022 inbound messages and SWIFT outbound messages.
- Involved in memory leak analysis to find the root cause of the issue and provided resolution

## Technologies

o Q5 (JPA), IBM websphere, Struts MVC, JAX-WS, Junit, Mockito

June 2005 to Dec 2007

## Java Developer for Tata Elxsi

These are POCs projects for Motorola Electronics

- ESA-ICC (Early Stage Accelerator-Internet Content Consumption)
  - Analysed, designed, programmed, tested, documented and maintained ICC

- application.
- Analysed requests for enhancements/changes and wrote amendment/program specification
- Developed STB App on top of OCAP-DVR API
- Involved in developed of Tribune client app which act as a SOAP Client to download EPG from tribute (Zap2it) server on daily basis.
- Developed server app using J2EE (JBOSS) which acts as an interface between Mobile and STB.
- IVC (Interactive Voice Client)
  - Developed GUI for DCT and Kreatel STB using OCAP DVR API and GTK respectively.
  - Developed Portal for Kreatel box using java Script.
- Technologies
  - Java, OCAP(Open Cable Application platform), SOAP Webservice

#### **Projects on GitHub**

: github

: Basic knowledge of C, Python, Pandas, Jupyter notebook

sahoo.rabindra@gmail.com • +44 (0)74591 99265 address - ..., EDINBURGH, UK pdf version • doc version